Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
It's been a year already.
Right.
It's like magic.
Maybe it is magic.
Oceans, skies... Earth did recover.
But sometimes I wonder if it's real.
In this vast universe, we happened
to meet, and now we're here.
Why don't we believe that
we're both part of this miracle ?
Like these oceans and skies...
...we're together because it's meant to be.
Kodai...
What's wrong ?
Nothing. Sorry.
Are you alright ?
You don't look...
Maybe I'm just relieved after seeing
your face after so many days.
So it's true that Mori doesn't remember...
She lost her memories of the past 4 years.
She's cured.
There you are, Team Ginga.
How is the Antares group doing ?
Welcome aboard the Yamato,
the place we call home.
It's a miracle that all the aerial squadrons
remained intact during such a dire situation.
How was the Ginga ?
We didn't really belong there since
most of its spacecraft are unmanned.
So, what do you think of the attacker ?
It's awesome.
Smaller turning radius,
lower turret motion rate...
It's so easy to handle.
It's a bit tight inside, though...
Then, you'll always be the gunner.
Hey, Shino, how's Commander Kato ?
Now that we're all here, let's go.
I lost the command A.I.,
on top of the Cosmo Reverse.
At this moment,
we can't proceed with Plan G.
Because of that, we'll transfer
some equipment to the Yamato.
The Ginga will stay here and prepare for the next...
That's good enough, Captain Todo.
I have some questions on how the command A.I. was destroyed, but this is wartime.
I need to let the field officers make decisions.
Thank you very much, Chief.
Soon, Earth will have to
fight a decisive battle here.
This could be the last time we talk like this.
I couldn't do anything for you...
...but if we could meet again...
Chief...
Father, I feel like
I understand Mother a little better.
Humans set goals because
of weak and fragile minds.
I've been thinking I'd be better off keeping
a closed mind if it became a burden, but...
It's fate that you met him on Telesart.
My Uncle...
...Abelt Desler was not a crazy dictator.
Planet Garmillas is dying,
but he had to keep it secret.
He cared about the future
of our people more than anyone.
I was able to learn that, so this assignment...
Happy about it ?
Are you going then ?
I'd like your permission.
This is a tough time for Garmillas.
We have to find a new home with a similar
environment for the entire population to migrate to.
I don't want to lose a talent who's suitable for the difficult task, but having seen your face...
You've lost your edge, Klaus.
Are you in love ?
Huh ?
I've realized that this weak and fragile
mind is what makes humans human.
Fickle and uncertain, but rational at times.
Activate
All useable parts on the
Ginga have been transferred.
You're not going to say
I'm the most needed, are you ?
You're not going with me.
Pops...
There's so much left for you to teach those kids.
Train them to be skilled engineers, Yamazaki.
That's human nature, which
can't be replaced with machines.
It's the source of our unique power, which is
so strong that we can actually hurt ourselves.
Hijikata, you were right about
the wave motion gun fleet...
...and overconfidence with power. In the end...
I just spoke for Okita. It was you who had
the practical insight about Earth's future.
But I couldn't see the future, and that
is what's at stake in the next battle.
We have a real challenge ahead of us.
You and I, as well as all mankind.
No matter what the future holds,
I want to be human until the very last moment.
Everyone's leaving the hospital ?
Yes. Let's get back to Earth and prepare
to welcome Dad and his friends home.
The 248th fleet has departed.
It'll coordinate with the advanced fleet
to form the second defense line.
You only need to stop them.
As long as we have the Time Fault,
Earth's war potential is...
Yamato...
Not just Tsubasa, but many other kids
with the same illness have been saved.
You should be happy.
I can't. Treason is treason.
Don't give me that face, Shino.
Everyone accepted me without saying a word.
I can't die until I repay my debt.
The enemy defense is overwhelming.
We lost the Ginga's wave motion amplifier...
...so neither Earth nor Garmillas has the necessary firepower to break through, except for...
The Transit wave motion gun.
Correct.
The Transit wave motion gun may be able to
break through the defense field of the comet city.
We aim at this location, and then open a
path to enter the heart of enemy territory.
Our taskforce will target Gatlantis's
Achilles heel, which is Zorder's throne.
That's Golem.
Katsuragi Touko told me just
before she passed out.
We'll activate Golem and destroy all of Gatlantis.
Total annihilation...?
They're not human. Don't bother.
One more time...
Can we talk to Zorder one more time ?
Kodai...
Maybe we can seize Golem
and use it as a bargaining chip.
You're too naive !
Have you forgotten what Gatlantis has done ?!
I haven't...
...but now I know their history...
...and Zorder's past...
I don't think I can convince a person who's been in despair for a thousand years.
Even so...
Fine.
If you find a chance, don't waste it.
But you must remember your limits.
Aye, sir.
Are you alright ?
I wonder why...
He stood up alone against everyone.
That's how he is.
And you fell in love with him.
I've never met anyone who is so deeply
in love with each other like you two.
I just wanted you to know that.
Say what ?!
The Space Cavalry will be excluded from this operation. That's the Captain's order.
Pops, explain why !
Stop, Saito !
There are other spies on board besides Katsuragi Touko.
From Kato's testimony, it appears to be true.
The Space Cavalry was rescued from the 11th Planet, which makes you guys the highest risk.
I have to put my faith in you.
What ?
You owe me one, Commander.
Once Touko regains consciousness,
we should be able to ask, but until then...
Tell me...
...tell me, how does one break
free from the puppeteer ?
Garmillas has taken some Gatlantian hostages.
There must be a way to prevent self detonation.
There's only one way.
That's...
Captain Hijikata.
Once the Yamato's destruction is confirmed,
we'll arrange a new home for Garmillas to migrate to.
Exactly the same environment as your dying planet.
No matter how vast the universe is,
only Gatlantis can do that.
Are you sure, Keyman ?
I can't see anything.
No abnormality in the external sensors, either.
I'm positive.
It was brief, but that was...
A man who values honor more than
anyone won't take deceptive actions...
Desler is serious.
We must end any
doubt once and for all !
All hands, prepare to warp !
Yamato means great harmony.
Your ideals may be beautiful.
However, ideals can't save anything.
If your ideals can change this reality,
then come get me, Ranhalt.
Did we get it ?
This close...
Core ship, emergency separation.
Enemy ship separated !
What ?
Prepare for reverse thrust !
No, keep going.
Crash into it !
No enemy contact, except
for one, the Neues Deusula !
No engine signature from the separated vessel.
Space Cavalry platoon, prepare for take off !
All hands, use B configuration !
Prepare for hand-to-hand combat !
Chief Tactical Officer Kodai will lead
Team Bravo and storm the enemy ship !
Lieutenant Keyman will manage the timing !
Kodai...
No response at all.
It's likely unmanned.
Why ?
Interference in the aft wave motion shield !
The wave motion shield has
weakened and is partially breached.
The armor has been damaged, and several small mobile Gatlantis weapons have entered the ship.
Team Alpha, guard the interior of the ship !
Also from ahead !
Detaching the core ship in exchange
for stopping the Yamato's movement...
Excellent split-second decision.
It's almost like you knew the
Yamato would crash into our ship.
You wouldn't understand...
...but family members tend to have similar ideas.
Turning left at the next corner !
The defense will be tough !
Got it !
What's the enemy status inside the ship ?
Their numbers are dwindling.
Commander Saito's Team Alpha is fighting well.
I just guided all the hostiles to you.
Got it.
Leave them to me.
Nagakura, when they touch
the trap, aim for the elbow.
Got it !
Commander !
Nagakura !
Damn, no use.
What are you doing, Commander ?
Beats me...
They need love.
They need love after all. How pitiful...
Know what despair is.
Don't tell me I...I'm...
Commander...?
Am I...
You kill each other without knowing
that you're just being toyed with by fate.
Know what despair is.
Kill everyone,
burn everything down, then go extinct.
That's how humans are.
They need love after all.
Not the kind of love to preserve the species.
Not the kind of love that'll fade away
because of a mere memory problem.
But love that will end this suffering.
Death will bring eternal peace to humans.
That's the greatest love of all.
They are puppets after all.
The control room's been breached ?
Why can't they eliminate such
a small number of rats ?
Führer, His Highness Ranhalt
knows everything about this ship.
Your word was not to interfere
with your family matters, but...
I don't remember changing my order.
But at this rate, you'll be in danger.
Let us send you a rescue team...
That was faster than I thought.
Führer, stop the fight at once.
You're using Gatlantis to save your people...
...aren't you ?
If so, why did you send me a signal ?
Zorder's objective is to
exterminate all human life in the universe.
Even if he keeps his promise,
they can never coexist with us.
Deep down, you know
you should ally with Earth.
That's why...
The salvation you achieved in the small
environment on the Yamato was trivial.
Führer...
Ranhalt...
Don't move.
Führer !
Klaus Keyman, kill Desler.
If you do, I'll spare both Earth and Garmillas.
Time doesn't mean anything to clones like us.
I wonder how many centuries it'd take
to exterminate the entire human race...
Do as I say, and you'll gain a 10,000 year extension.
Now kill Desler, an object of your love !
Episode 22
Destined Duel !
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Saijo Miki :
Kato Saburo:
Kato Makoto:
Kato Tsubasa:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Yamamoto Akira:
Sawamura Sho:
Takuma Takeshi:
Yamazaki Susumu:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Kenich Suzumura
Otsuka Hochu
Mugihito
Akabane Kenji
Moriya Satomi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Sato Rina
Takamori Natsumi
Hirakawa Daisuke
Tanaka Rie
Shikaki  Yuya
Kijima Koichi
Tsuchida Hiroshi
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Kurata Masaru:
Todo Saki:
Hijikata Ryu:
Yamanami Osamu:
Todo Heikuro:
Serizawa Kotetsu
Operator:
Tochi Hiroyuki
Amagai Kazusa
Kiyohito Yoshikai
Takagaki Ayahi
Kusumi Naomi
Ebara Masashi
Kojima Toshihiko
Genda Tessho
Fujinuma Kento
Cottony clouds drift high across the sky
Sora takaku nagareru kieyuku wata no kumo
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Loren Barrel:
Gadel Talan:
Zorder:
Mill:
Yamadera Koichi
Kamiya Hiroshi
Terasoma Masaki
Nakamura Kotaro
Tezuka Hideaki
Uchiyama Koki
Holding out both hands, I stretch out in the falling leaves
Ryoote wo age ah senobi shita rakuyou
As the house lights come on, I wish to meet people smiling at each other
Akari tomoru mado waraiau hito ni aitai to omou
Believing in a miraculous enounter to become real, I shout out for love
Sou kanau hazusa kiseki no deai ni ai sakenda
Luminous lives meet and bond with each other
Kagayaku jinsei no meguriawase tsumuideyuku
Let’s keep on living our lives
Bokura no jinsei wo tayumazu ni susumi tsuzukeyou
Let’s begin the story of our lives
Bokura no jinsei no monogatari wo saa hajimeyou
Preview
Now young Desler, choose your future.
Shoot, Ranhalt.
Death is not the hardest thing for humans.
If you don't choose, what's the point ?!
Don't ! You shouldn't choose !
Kodai !
Episode 23
Soldiers of Love